Andi Miller

West View Cottage Phone: 07837 429193

Upperton Email: andi@andimiller.net Petworth IRC: Sylnai@irc.freenode.net West Sussex Homepage: andimiller.net

GU28 9BE

Portfolio: https://github.com/andimiller/

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

LANGUAGES

Scala My main day to day language at DataSift, both in a java interoperable style, and in a functional style.

 \mathbf{C} Covered during my degree, used it for university work and personal projects, wrote patches for OpenSIPS and Asterisk while at Gradwell.

С# Learnt while at College, used for many personal projects including a network monitor, a few small games, some of which had network capabilities.

Used during university for academic projects and used for multiple projects at DataSift. Java PHP Maintained old PHP webapps at Gradwell and DataSift, using it for some of my own sites

Python Worked on Jokosher and PiTiVi as part of the Google Summer of Code, used for many personal projects including pizza-auth, a large scale LDAP user management tool for EVE Online alliances.

TECHNOLOGIES

Large Stream Processing At DataSift I gained experience building scalable stream processing systems with

technologies including kafka, zeromq and redis.

Big Data I also have experience with Hadoop and ELK for storing and indexing large

I enjoy writing parallel processing jobs, and have used python, hadoop and spark Parallel Programming

for it.

Network Protocols Have implimented a variety protocols in many languages, including IRC, HTTP,

FTP and NTP.

Server Admin Have experience with managing many types of servers, including various Linux

and BSD distrubutions, and Windows Server. Also maintain my own VPS for

personal use running Debian.

Typesetting Writing up many project reports, and this CV in IATEX. I have also written a

couple of LATEX to HTML converters.

UNIX and Linux After using *NIX systems for many years, I am more than competent at admin-

istering systems running a *NIX-like Operating System.

Version Control When coding I've used lots of Version Control systems, including SVN, Git,

Mercurial and Bazaar.

Virtualisation I maintain a set of Virtual Machines for testing personal projects, and have

experience administering KVM and OpenVZ clusters.

Web Development I maintain multiple websites in my spare time, and am familiar with modern web

development practices including HTML5, CSS, Websockets and Scala.js.

Andi Miller 2

EDUCATION

```
B.Eng. Software Engineering, Aberystwyth University, 2009 - 2013.
```

2:1, just below a First

Averaged over 70% in core Programming modules.

Alton College, Alton, Surrey 2006 - 2008

A-Levels: Further Maths - C, Maths - A, Physics - B, Computing - A.

AS-Level: Electronics - B.

Churchers College, Petersfield, Hampshire, 2000 - 2006.

GCSE: 2 A*'s, 4 A's, 3 B's, 2 C's

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer, DataSift (MediaSift Ltd.), June 2013 - Present

Worked in an angile team developing scala microservices.

Practiced agile test driven development in a team.

Developed and maintained an in-house Domain Specific Language for transforming JSON

Maintained client-facing API libraries and their documentation

VoIP Engineer, Gradwell dot com Limited, June 2011 to July 2012.

Maintained and made improvements to one of the largest award-winning Open Source VoIP stacks in the UK.

Regularly worked with both Support and System Administration departments.

Worked in a variety of languages, including Perl, C, Python and Ruby.

Worked in an engineering team using Jira and Mercurial.

Freelance Coder (Google Summer of Code), Google, Summer 2010.

Worked to a strict deadline

Integrated into the community

Learned many new technologies, including:

DBus

GTK

Bazaar

REFERENCES

Available on request.

Last updated: November 9, 2015 http://andimiller.net/